{
  "chapters": [
    {
      "chapter_number": 1,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 1,
          "question": "From what perspective is the narrative of Lord of the Flies related?",
          "options": [
            "Second person.",
            "Fourth person.",
            "First person.",
            "Third person."
          ],
          "answer": "Third person."
        },
        {
          "number": 2,
          "question": "What physical ailment does Piggy say he suffers from in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "Partial deafness.",
            "Tuberculosis.",
            "Asthma.",
            "Epilepsy."
          ],
          "answer": "Asthma."
        },
        {
          "number": 3,
          "question": "Piggy tells Ralph in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell” that he’s worn glasses since he was how old?",
          "options": [
            "3.",
            "4.",
            "2.",
            "6."
          ],
          "answer": "3."
        },
        {
          "number": 4,
          "question": "How old is Ralph said to be in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "10.",
            "8.",
            "15.",
            "12."
          ],
          "answer": "12."
        },
        {
          "number": 5,
          "question": "Ralph tells Piggy in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell” that his father holds what position?",
          "options": [
            "Magazine Editor.",
            "Journalist.",
            "Commander of the Navy.",
            "Ambassador to Egypt."
          ],
          "answer": "Commander of the Navy."
        },
        {
          "number": 6,
          "question": "How old does Ralph say he was when his father taught him to swim in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "2.",
            "5.",
            "6.",
            "8."
          ],
          "answer": "5."
        },
        {
          "number": 7,
          "question": "What is Piggy’s answer when Ralph asks him in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell,” “What’s your father?”",
          "options": [
            "“My dad is a carpenter.”",
            "“My dad’s dead.”",
            "“My dad left us.”",
            "“My dad is a butcher.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“My dad’s dead.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 8,
          "question": "What kind of store does Piggy say his auntie used to run in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "A shoe store.",
            "A candy store.",
            "A women’s clothing store.",
            "A florist shop."
          ],
          "answer": "A candy store."
        },
        {
          "number": 9,
          "question": "What kind of shell do Ralph and Piggy discover on the beach in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "A slipper shell.",
            "An alphabet cone.",
            "A conch shell.",
            "A Florida auger."
          ],
          "answer": "A conch shell."
        },
        {
          "number": 10,
          "question": "The first boy that appears after Ralph blows the sounds on the shell is said to be about how old in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "6.",
            "3.",
            "8.",
            "10."
          ],
          "answer": "6."
        },
        {
          "number": 11,
          "question": "What is the name of the first little boy that arrives from the jungle when Ralph blows on the shell in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "Maurice.",
            "Johnny.",
            "Henry.",
            "Simon."
          ],
          "answer": "Johnny."
        },
        {
          "number": 12,
          "question": "What are the names of the twins that appear on the beach in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "Sam and Eric.",
            "Simon and Johnny.",
            "Roger and Robert.",
            "Percival and Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Sam and Eric."
        },
        {
          "number": 13,
          "question": "What are the boys from the choir wearing when they arrive on the beach in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "Military uniforms.",
            "High-collared uniforms.",
            "Swimsuits.",
            "Black cloaks."
          ],
          "answer": "Black cloaks."
        },
        {
          "number": 14,
          "question": "What color is Jack Merridew’s hair in the novel?",
          "options": [
            "Brown.",
            "Red.",
            "Black.",
            "Blonde."
          ],
          "answer": "Red."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 2,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 15,
          "question": "Who suggests that the boys hold a vote for the chief in Chapter 1: “The Sound of the Shell”?",
          "options": [
            "Roger.",
            "Simon.",
            "Henry.",
            "Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 16,
          "question": "What kinds of wild animals have the boys discovered living on the island in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Deer.",
            "Turkeys.",
            "Pigs.",
            "Foxes."
          ],
          "answer": "Pigs."
        },
        {
          "number": 17,
          "question": "One of the rules that Ralph establishes at the meeting in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain” is that no one may speak at the meetings unless he is holding what?",
          "options": [
            "The staff.",
            "The spear.",
            "The shell.",
            "The stone."
          ],
          "answer": "The shell."
        },
        {
          "number": 18,
          "question": "What color is the birthmark described as on the young boy who steps forward at the meeting in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Crimson-colored.",
            "Violet-colored.",
            "Mulberry-colored.",
            "Black-colored."
          ],
          "answer": "Mulberry-colored."
        },
        {
          "number": 19,
          "question": "What does the boy with the birthmark first call “the beastie” in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "“The snake-thing.”",
            "“The wolf-thing.”",
            "“The bird-thing.”",
            "“The bear-thing.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“The snake-thing.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 20,
          "question": "Where are the boys in Lord of the Flies from originally?",
          "options": [
            "The United States.",
            "Ireland.",
            "England.",
            "France."
          ],
          "answer": "England."
        },
        {
          "number": 21,
          "question": "Who leads the boys to the mountaintop in order to begin building a signal fire in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Johnny.",
            "Ralph.",
            "Jack.",
            "Henry."
          ],
          "answer": "Jack."
        },
        {
          "number": 22,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word “ebullience,” used in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Luxuriance.",
            "Exhilaration.",
            "Belligerence.",
            "Vicissitude."
          ],
          "answer": "Exhilaration."
        },
        {
          "number": 23,
          "question": "Who is the only boy who does not help gather firewood in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Simon.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Ralph."
          ],
          "answer": "Piggy."
        },
        {
          "number": 24,
          "question": "The members of the choir have adjusted their choir hats to resemble what, in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Berets.",
            "Fedoras.",
            "Wizard hats.",
            "Cowboy hats."
          ],
          "answer": "Berets."
        },
        {
          "number": 25,
          "question": "Which of the boys are thoughtful enough to bring leaves for the signal fire in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon and Peter.",
            "Johnny and Percival.",
            "Sam and Eric.",
            "Henry and Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Henry and Maurice."
        },
        {
          "number": 26,
          "question": "When the boys are trying to figure out how to light a fire in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain,” who says, “You make a bow and spin the arrow”?",
          "options": [
            "Johnny.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Simon.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 27,
          "question": "Who suggests the boys use Piggy’s glasses to start the fire in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "Henry.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Jack.",
            "Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Jack."
        },
        {
          "number": 28,
          "question": "When the choir assumes guardianship of the fire, what group within them is assigned fire-duty during the first week in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "The sopranos.",
            "The trebles.",
            "The altos.",
            "The basses."
          ],
          "answer": "The altos."
        },
        {
          "number": 29,
          "question": "The author uses the following sentence in Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”: “The flames, as though they were a kind of wild life, crept as a jaguar creeps on its belly toward a line of birch-like saplings that fledged an outcrop of the pink rock.” What literary technique is used in this sentence?",
          "options": [
            "Personification.",
            "Literary allusion.",
            "Onomatopoeia.",
            "Simile."
          ],
          "answer": "Simile."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 3,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 30,
          "question": "Which “littlun” is unaccounted for at the end of Chapter 2: “Fire on the Mountain”?",
          "options": [
            "The boy with the birthmark.",
            "The boy with the glasses.",
            "Henry.",
            "The boy with the wheelchair."
          ],
          "answer": "The boy with the birthmark."
        },
        {
          "number": 31,
          "question": "What color eyes is Jack said to have in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Blue.",
            "Black.",
            "Green.",
            "Brown."
          ],
          "answer": "Blue."
        },
        {
          "number": 32,
          "question": "In Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach,” the narrator states, “The silence of the forest was more oppressive than” what?",
          "options": [
            "“The danger.”",
            "“The isolation.”",
            "“The heat.”",
            "“The permanence.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“The heat.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 33,
          "question": "What color are the pig droppings that Jack finds in the forest in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Reddish brown.",
            "Olive green.",
            "Dark brown.",
            "Solid black."
          ],
          "answer": "Olive green."
        },
        {
          "number": 34,
          "question": "What does the word “vicissitude” mean, as used in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Savagery.",
            "A change or variation.",
            "A gathering of people.",
            "A betrayal of principles."
          ],
          "answer": "A change or variation."
        },
        {
          "number": 35,
          "question": "What does Jack ask Ralph for when he arrives at the camp in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Water.",
            "The shell.",
            "Piggy's glass.",
            "A spear."
          ],
          "answer": "Water."
        },
        {
          "number": 36,
          "question": "Who is the only boy that is helping Ralph build the shelters in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Johnny.",
            "Henry.",
            "Simon.",
            "Jack."
          ],
          "answer": "Simon."
        },
        {
          "number": 37,
          "question": "When Jack arrives at the huts, Ralph says that his hunters have been back at camp hours ago and have been doing what, in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Swimming.",
            "Sunbathing.",
            "Building a boat.",
            "Making sand castles."
          ],
          "answer": "Swimming."
        },
        {
          "number": 38,
          "question": "What weapons have Jack and the choir boys devised for hunting game on the island in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Guns.",
            "Blowguns.",
            "Spears.",
            "Bows and arrows."
          ],
          "answer": "Spears."
        },
        {
          "number": 39,
          "question": "What word used in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach” refers to a downward slope of ground?",
          "options": [
            "Simile.",
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Exhilaration.",
            "Declivity."
          ],
          "answer": "Declivity."
        },
        {
          "number": 40,
          "question": "What color hair is Simon said to have in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Blonde.",
            "Brown.",
            "Red.",
            "Black."
          ],
          "answer": "Black."
        },
        {
          "number": 41,
          "question": "What does Simon hand to the littluns after they’ve followed him into the forest in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Candy.",
            "Spears.",
            "Fruit.",
            "Meat."
          ],
          "answer": "Fruit."
        },
        {
          "number": 42,
          "question": "What does the word “furtive” mean, as used in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Savage.",
            "Stealthy.",
            "Pointless.",
            "Personalized."
          ],
          "answer": "Stealthy."
        },
        {
          "number": 43,
          "question": "What word used in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach” refers to the individual leaves or parts of the calyx of a flower?",
          "options": [
            "Plots.",
            "Cultivars.",
            "Sepals.",
            "Stamens."
          ],
          "answer": "Sepals."
        },
        {
          "number": 44,
          "question": "Between what two characters is there a developing conflict that is foreshadowed in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach”?",
          "options": [
            "Henry and Maurice.",
            "Simon and Maurice.",
            "Jack and Ralph.",
            "Piggy and Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Jack and Ralph."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 4,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 45,
          "question": "What word used in Chapter 3: “Huts on the Beach” is an adjective indicating that something is under the surface?",
          "options": [
            "Obstinate.",
            "Declivity.",
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Submerged."
          ],
          "answer": "Submerged."
        },
        {
          "number": 46,
          "question": "Of the boys on the island, the narrator says in the beginning of Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair,” “They accepted the pleasures of morning, the bright sun, the whelming sea and sweet air, as a time when play was good and life so full that” what “was not necessary and therefore forgotten”?",
          "options": [
            "“Sorrow.”",
            "“Mankind.”",
            "“Faith.”",
            "“Hope.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Hope.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 47,
          "question": "What word does Piggy use in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair” to refer to images that appeared on the horizon and then disappeared as the boys watched?",
          "options": [
            "Correlation.",
            "Simile.",
            "Mirage.",
            "Declivity."
          ],
          "answer": "Mirage."
        },
        {
          "number": 48,
          "question": "The narrator says in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair,” “At midday the illusions merged into the sky and there the sun gazed down like” what?",
          "options": [
            "“A great bird.”",
            "“A parent’s eye.”",
            "“A loving overlord.”",
            "“An angry eye.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“An angry eye.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 49,
          "question": "What literary technique is used in the following sentence from Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”? “When the sun sank, darkness dropped on the island like an extinguisher.”",
          "options": [
            "Onomatopoeia.",
            "Literary allusion.",
            "Dramatic irony.",
            "Simile."
          ],
          "answer": "Simile."
        },
        {
          "number": 50,
          "question": "What is the name of the littlun that the narrator describes crawling into a shelter and staying there for two days, “talking, singing, and crying, till they thought him batty and were faintly amused” in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "Percival.",
            "Johnny.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Henry."
          ],
          "answer": "Percival."
        },
        {
          "number": 51,
          "question": "Of the three littluns that are described together playing by the sandcastles in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair,” who is described as “the biggest of them”?",
          "options": [
            "Henry.",
            "Percival.",
            "Simon.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Henry."
        },
        {
          "number": 52,
          "question": "Who are described as “the smallest boys on the island” in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "Jack and Ralph.",
            "Roger and Robert.",
            "Henry and Simon.",
            "Percival and Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Percival and Johnny."
        },
        {
          "number": 53,
          "question": "What word used in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair” refers to a warlike or aggressively hostile nature or attitude?",
          "options": [
            "Declivity.",
            "Mirage.",
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Belligerence."
          ],
          "answer": "Belligerence."
        },
        {
          "number": 54,
          "question": "Which of the older boys leads the way through the sand castles, kicking them over and laughing, in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Roger.",
            "Robert.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 55,
          "question": "Which of the boys had, in his “other life… received chastisement for filling a younger eye with sand,” according to the narrator in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Robert.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice."
        },
        {
          "number": 56,
          "question": "What ocean is described as surrounding the island in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "The Pacific Ocean.",
            "The Atlantic Ocean.",
            "The Indian Ocean.",
            "The Arctic Ocean."
          ],
          "answer": "The Pacific Ocean."
        },
        {
          "number": 57,
          "question": "Which of the littluns does Roger follow to the beach and begin throwing stones at in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "Johnny.",
            "Simon.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Henry."
          ],
          "answer": "Henry."
        },
        {
          "number": 58,
          "question": "Which of the littluns had run off crying after getting sand in his eye in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "Henry.",
            "Percival.",
            "Johnny.",
            "Ralph."
          ],
          "answer": "Percival."
        },
        {
          "number": 59,
          "question": "Which of the littluns has been left “in triumphant possession of the castles” after the others have run off in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair”?",
          "options": [
            "James.",
            "Johnny.",
            "Henry.",
            "Simon."
          ],
          "answer": "Johnny."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 5,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 60,
          "question": "Who is described in Chapter 4: “Painted Faces and Long Hair” as “the only boy on the island whose hair never seemed to grow”?",
          "options": [
            "Piggy.",
            "Simon.",
            "Jack.",
            "Ralph."
          ],
          "answer": "Piggy."
        },
        {
          "number": 61,
          "question": "The narrator says of Ralph in the beginning of Chapter 5: “Beast from Water,” “He found himself understanding the wearisomeness of this life, where every path was an improvisation and a considerable part of one’s waking life was spent watching” what?",
          "options": [
            "“One’s feet.”",
            "“One’s back.”",
            "“The road ahead.”",
            "“The road behind.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“One’s feet.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 62,
          "question": "What word from Chapter 5: “Beast from Water” refers to a contortion of the body caused by violent, involuntary muscular contractions?",
          "options": [
            "Exhilaration.",
            "Convulsion.",
            "Declivity.",
            "Belligerence."
          ],
          "answer": "Convulsion."
        },
        {
          "number": 63,
          "question": "As Ralph prepares for the assembly in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water” he considers to himself, “I can’t think. Not like” whom?",
          "options": [
            "“Jack.”",
            "“Johnny.”",
            "“Piggy.”",
            "“Simon.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Piggy.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 64,
          "question": "What word, used to describe Ralph’s feelings about the shell in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water,” refers to a feeling of deep respect tinged with awe?",
          "options": [
            "Belligerence.",
            "Simile.",
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Reverence."
          ],
          "answer": "Reverence."
        },
        {
          "number": 65,
          "question": "Who does Ralph say will be guarding the fire that night during the assembly in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "Sam and Eric.",
            "Maurice and Roger.",
            "Johnny and Jack.",
            "Robert and Percival."
          ],
          "answer": "Sam and Eric."
        },
        {
          "number": 66,
          "question": "How many of the boys does Ralph say built the second shelter in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "2.",
            "10.",
            "6.",
            "4."
          ],
          "answer": "4."
        },
        {
          "number": 67,
          "question": "Ralph wheels on the hunters during the assembly in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water” and says “You can laugh! But I tell you the smoke is more important than” what?",
          "options": [
            "“The pig.”",
            "“The snake.”",
            "“The beast.”",
            "“The birds.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“The pig.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 68,
          "question": "During Piggy’s speech at the podium during the assembly he declares that “Life is” what, in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "“Meaningless.”",
            "“Hopeful.”",
            "“Futile.”",
            "“Scientific.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Scientific.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 69,
          "question": "When does Piggy surmise the war will be over when he speaks at the assembly in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "A year or two.",
            "Tomorrow or the next day.",
            "In a few months.",
            "Three or four years."
          ],
          "answer": "A year or two."
        },
        {
          "number": 70,
          "question": "What is the name of the littlun that first steps forward to talk about the beast during the assembly in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Phil.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Phil."
        },
        {
          "number": 71,
          "question": "Who stands up at the assembly and claims he was alone in the forest at night in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Jack.",
            "Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Simon."
        },
        {
          "number": 72,
          "question": "What is Percival’s full name that he states in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "Percival William Jackson.",
            "Percival Wemys Madison.",
            "Percival James Anderson.",
            "Percival Henry Waterson."
          ],
          "answer": "Percival Wemys Madison."
        },
        {
          "number": 73,
          "question": "Who performs clownishly at the assembly in order to make the littluns stop wailing in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "Jack.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Ralph.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice."
        },
        {
          "number": 74,
          "question": "As Simon attempts to speak during the assembly in Chapter 5: “Beast from Water,” the narrator states, “Simon became inarticulate in his effort to express mankind’s essential” what?",
          "options": [
            "“Beauty.”",
            "“Hope.”",
            "“Reverence.”",
            "“Illness.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Illness.”"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 6,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 75,
          "question": "Who, in addition to Piggy, tries to convince Ralph not to give up his position as chief at the end of Chapter 5: “Beast from Water”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Robert.",
            "Jack."
          ],
          "answer": "Simon."
        },
        {
          "number": 76,
          "question": "Who picks up Percival and carries him to a shelter in the beginning of Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "Jack and Roger.",
            "Piggy and Simon.",
            "Robert and Henry.",
            "Ralph and Simon."
          ],
          "answer": "Ralph and Simon."
        },
        {
          "number": 77,
          "question": "Of the twins, the narrator says in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air” that “they could never manage to do things sensibly if that meant” what?",
          "options": [
            "“Being patient.”",
            "“Acting independently.”",
            "“Working toward a goal.”",
            "“Taking orders.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Acting independently.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 78,
          "question": "One of the twins asks the other if he remembers what character from school in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "“Old Gremlin.”",
            "“Old Wizard.”",
            "“Old Waxy.”",
            "“Old Potters.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Old Waxy.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 79,
          "question": "Ralph lies in the shelter dreaming of feeding what farm animals when Sam and Eric arrive in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "Pigs.",
            "Ponies.",
            "Ducks.",
            "Chickens."
          ],
          "answer": "Ponies."
        },
        {
          "number": 80,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word “interminable,” used in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "Cruel.",
            "Unending.",
            "Near-sighted.",
            "Far-sighted."
          ],
          "answer": "Unending."
        },
        {
          "number": 81,
          "question": "Who slaps Johnny when he bursts into tears during the impromptu meeting the morning after the beast has been spotted in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "Henry.",
            "Bill.",
            "Jack.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Bill."
        },
        {
          "number": 82,
          "question": "Who suggests at the impromptu meeting in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air,” “Couldn’t we—kind of—stay here? Maybe the beast won’t come near us”?",
          "options": [
            "Phil.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Jack.",
            "Bill."
          ],
          "answer": "Piggy."
        },
        {
          "number": 83,
          "question": "As the big boys set out to hunt down the beast in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air,” the narrator states, “This day promised, like the others, to be a sunbath under” what?",
          "options": [
            "“A blue dome.”",
            "“A parched sky.”",
            "“A violent sky.”",
            "“A red dome.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“A blue dome.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 84,
          "question": "What adjective used in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air” to describe Simon means lacking confidence in one’s own ability, worth, or fitness?",
          "options": [
            "Opulent.",
            "Diffident.",
            "Belligerent.",
            "Reverent."
          ],
          "answer": "Diffident."
        },
        {
          "number": 85,
          "question": "What color is the cliff of rock that forms the side of the castle described as in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "White.",
            "Green.",
            "Blue.",
            "Pink."
          ],
          "answer": "Pink."
        },
        {
          "number": 86,
          "question": "The word “leviathan” that is used in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air” refers to what?",
          "options": [
            "A sea monster.",
            "A political organization.",
            "A spaceship.",
            "A hawk."
          ],
          "answer": "A sea monster."
        },
        {
          "number": 87,
          "question": "The “half-cave” that Ralph and Jack encounter while looking for the beast is said to contain “nothing more terrible than a clutch of” what, in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air”?",
          "options": [
            "“Baby pigs.”",
            "“Rotten eggs.”",
            "“Rotten fruit.”",
            "“Spears.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Rotten eggs.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 88,
          "question": "When Jack suggests that “the castle” would make an excellent fort in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air,” this is an example of what literary technique?",
          "options": [
            "Religious allusion.",
            "Interrogation.",
            "Foreshadowing.",
            "Onomatopoeia."
          ],
          "answer": "Foreshadowing."
        },
        {
          "number": 89,
          "question": "Which of the boys comes up to Ralph at the castle to ask in Chapter 6: “Beast from Air,” “Why can’t we stay here for a bit?”",
          "options": [
            "Jack.",
            "Henry.",
            "Bill.",
            "Simon."
          ],
          "answer": "Bill."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 7,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 90,
          "question": "What British slang word is used throughout the narrative to mean excellent or wonderful?",
          "options": [
            "“Masterly.”",
            "“Wizard.”",
            "“Doge.”",
            "“Rad.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Wizard.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 91,
          "question": "In the beginning of Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees,” Ralph wishes that he had a pair of scissors to do what?",
          "options": [
            "Cut his hair.",
            "Cut a boat sail.",
            "Cut his shorts.",
            "Cut his shirt sleeves."
          ],
          "answer": "Cut his hair."
        },
        {
          "number": 92,
          "question": "What word does Ralph use in referring to a bath in the beginning of Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Declivity.",
            "Sepals.",
            "Frolic.",
            "Wallow."
          ],
          "answer": "Wallow."
        },
        {
          "number": 93,
          "question": "What does the imagery surrounding the vast sea symbolize in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Brotherly love.",
            "Ralph’s mother.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Eternity."
          ],
          "answer": "Eternity."
        },
        {
          "number": 94,
          "question": "What word used in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees” refers to the quality of being dulled or rounded at the extremity?",
          "options": [
            "Declivity.",
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Obtuseness.",
            "Belligerence."
          ],
          "answer": "Obtuseness."
        },
        {
          "number": 95,
          "question": "What does Simon whisper to Ralph as Ralph sits engulfed in staring at the sea in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "“Don’t worry. Jack won’t kill you.”",
            "“I’ve seen the Lord of the Flies.”",
            "“I’m sure that your father is out there somewhere.”",
            "“You’ll get back to where you came from.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“You’ll get back to where you came from.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 96,
          "question": "In Ralph’s memory in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees,” he recalls following his father from Chatham to where?",
          "options": [
            "New York.",
            "Davenport.",
            "Willoughby.",
            "London."
          ],
          "answer": "Davenport."
        },
        {
          "number": 97,
          "question": "Who acts as Ralph’s witness that he hit the boar with the spear in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees,” saying “I saw you. Right bang on his snout—Wheee!”?",
          "options": [
            "Maurice.",
            "Sam.",
            "Jack.",
            "Piggy."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice."
        },
        {
          "number": 98,
          "question": "Simon makes an allusion to what English Queen in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Queen Elizabeth.",
            "Berengaria of Navarre.",
            "Queen Victoria.",
            "Eleanor of Rigby."
          ],
          "answer": "Berengaria of Navarre."
        },
        {
          "number": 99,
          "question": "When the boys reenact the battle for the boar in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees,” which of the boys portrays the boar?",
          "options": [
            "Jack.",
            "Simon.",
            "Robert.",
            "Sam."
          ],
          "answer": "Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 100,
          "question": "Who suggests that the boys need a drum after the pig-killing ritual in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Johnny.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Jack.",
            "Percival."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice."
        },
        {
          "number": 101,
          "question": "Who says that the boys can’t go start a fire on the mountain because they don’t have the spectacles in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Maurice.",
            "Roger.",
            "Robert.",
            "Jack."
          ],
          "answer": "Jack."
        },
        {
          "number": 102,
          "question": "What word from Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees” means rich abundance or lushness?",
          "options": [
            "Luxuriance.",
            "Diffidence.",
            "Belligerence.",
            "Vicissitude."
          ],
          "answer": "Luxuriance."
        },
        {
          "number": 103,
          "question": "Who cuts his knee quite badly as the boys move along the rocks of the shoreline in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Jack.",
            "Robert.",
            "Ralph.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 104,
          "question": "Who is back at the shelters with the littluns as the other boys are on the hunt for the beast in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Ralph.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Simon."
          ],
          "answer": "Piggy."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 8,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 105,
          "question": "Who agrees to go back through the forest to the shelters and the littluns as the other boys head toward the mountain in Chapter 7: “Shadows and Tall Trees”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Jack."
          ],
          "answer": "Simon."
        },
        {
          "number": 106,
          "question": "Jack tells his hunters at the meeting in the beginning of Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness” that Ralph said they are all what?",
          "options": [
            "Monsters.",
            "Murderers.",
            "Cowards.",
            "Savages."
          ],
          "answer": "Cowards."
        },
        {
          "number": 107,
          "question": "Jack claims at the meeting in the beginning of Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness” that Ralph “says things like” whom?",
          "options": [
            "Prefect.",
            "Minaret.",
            "Sepal.",
            "Charlatan."
          ],
          "answer": "Minaret."
        },
        {
          "number": 108,
          "question": "What word does Jack use in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness” that refers to a person appointed to a position of command or authority?",
          "options": [
            "Charlatan.",
            "Minaret.",
            "Sepal.",
            "Prefect."
          ],
          "answer": "Prefect."
        },
        {
          "number": 109,
          "question": "How many of the boys raise their hands when Jack demands of them, “Who thinks Ralph oughtn’t to be chief?” in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "0.",
            "3.",
            "10.",
            "2."
          ],
          "answer": "0."
        },
        {
          "number": 110,
          "question": "What suggestion does Simon make when he takes the shell at the meeting in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "“I think we ought to follow Jack.”",
            "“I think we ought to climb the mountain.”",
            "“I think we ought to return to the shelter.”",
            "“I think we ought to call your auntie.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“I think we ought to climb the mountain.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 111,
          "question": "Piggy suggests to the boys that they rebuild the fire where, in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "At the Castle Rock.",
            "On the mountain.",
            "In the forest.",
            "On the beach."
          ],
          "answer": "On the beach."
        },
        {
          "number": 112,
          "question": "The narrator states in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness,” “The greatest ideas are the” what?",
          "options": [
            "“Most complex.”",
            "“Hardest.”",
            "“Simplest.”",
            "“Most derisive.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Simplest.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 113,
          "question": "Who lights the new fire in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Johnny.",
            "Jack."
          ],
          "answer": "Piggy."
        },
        {
          "number": 114,
          "question": "What do the twins and Piggy bring back to Ralph from the forest in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "Water.",
            "Fire.",
            "Meat.",
            "Fruit."
          ],
          "answer": "Fruit."
        },
        {
          "number": 115,
          "question": "How are the hunters able to find the wounded sow in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "By the trail of blood.",
            "By the trail of her piglets.",
            "By the squealing sounds.",
            "By the smell of her."
          ],
          "answer": "By the trail of blood."
        },
        {
          "number": 116,
          "question": "Who cuts the sow’s neck with a knife in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "Jack.",
            "Ralph.",
            "Simon.",
            "Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Jack."
        },
        {
          "number": 117,
          "question": "In the reenactment of the pig killing in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness,” who portrays the sow?",
          "options": [
            "Roger.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Jack.",
            "Robert."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice."
        },
        {
          "number": 118,
          "question": "In the reenactment of the killing of the pig in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness,” who portrays the killer?",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Jack.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 119,
          "question": "Who asks Jack as he disembowels the pig, “How can we make a fire?” in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "Roger.",
            "Percival.",
            "Henry.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 9,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 120,
          "question": "Which of the boys pick up and carry the pig after the kill in Chapter 8: “Gift for the Darkness”?",
          "options": [
            "Piggy and Percival.",
            "Simon and Ralph.",
            "Henry and Jack.",
            "Maurice and Robert."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice and Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 121,
          "question": "What ailment does Simon seemingly suffer from in Lord of the Flies?",
          "options": [
            "Asthma.",
            "Color-blindness.",
            "Epilepsy",
            "Tuberculosis."
          ],
          "answer": "Epilepsy"
        },
        {
          "number": 122,
          "question": "What is impaled on the stick that is referred as “The Lord of the Flies” in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "A human head.",
            "A horse’s head.",
            "A dead bird.",
            "A pig’s head."
          ],
          "answer": "A pig’s head."
        },
        {
          "number": 123,
          "question": "What does Simon say when he first speaks aloud in the jungle in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "“Where is the Lord of the Flies?”",
            "“What else is there to do?”",
            "“Why can’t I get home?”",
            "“Where are Jack and the others?”"
          ],
          "answer": "“What else is there to do?”"
        },
        {
          "number": 124,
          "question": "What part of his body gives Simon frequent pain as he makes his way through the jungle in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "His leg.",
            "His tongue.",
            "His back.",
            "His arm."
          ],
          "answer": "His tongue."
        },
        {
          "number": 125,
          "question": "What does Simon discover “the beast” to actually be in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "A severed pig’s head impaled on a stick.",
            "A dead water buffalo.",
            "A part of a plane engine.",
            "A dead pilot attached to a parachute."
          ],
          "answer": "A dead pilot attached to a parachute."
        },
        {
          "number": 126,
          "question": "What does Ralph tell Piggy is “the only thing to do” in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "“Calling Ralph’s auntie.”",
            "“Bathing.”",
            "“Going to the mountain.”",
            "“Begging for help.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Bathing.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 127,
          "question": "When Ralph and Piggy arrive at the feast in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death,” which of the boys, “thinking that Ralph had turned to him accusingly, put down his gnawed bone with a nervous giggle”?",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Jack.",
            "Roger.",
            "Sam."
          ],
          "answer": "Sam."
        },
        {
          "number": 128,
          "question": "The narrator notes when the feast begins to die down in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death,” “Evening was come, not with calm beauty but with” what?",
          "options": [
            "“The power of sacrifice.”",
            "“The threat of rain.”",
            "“The threat of violence.”",
            "“A solemn reverence.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“The threat of violence.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 129,
          "question": "Who obeys when Jack orders “Give me a drink” after he’s eaten at the feast in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "Johnny.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Percival.",
            "Henry."
          ],
          "answer": "Henry."
        },
        {
          "number": 130,
          "question": "What does Jack say “doesn’t count at this end of the island” in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "“The stone.”",
            "“The king.”",
            "“The conch.”",
            "“The torch.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“The conch.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 131,
          "question": "Who portrays the pig in the ritual dance after the feast in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "Roger.",
            "Simon.",
            "Ralph.",
            "Piggy."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 132,
          "question": "What word used Chapter 9: “A View to a Death” means crazy or insane?",
          "options": [
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Belligerence.",
            "Declivity.",
            "Demented."
          ],
          "answer": "Demented."
        },
        {
          "number": 133,
          "question": "After the ritual in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death,” the narrator says, “Along the shoreward edge of the shallows the advancing clearness was full of strange, moonbeam-bodied creatures with” what?",
          "options": [
            "“Fiery eyes.”",
            "“Mystical eyes.”",
            "“Eyes like opals.”",
            "“Hopeful eyes.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Fiery eyes.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 134,
          "question": "Which of the boys is killed during the ritual in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Jack.",
            "Piggy."
          ],
          "answer": "Simon."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 10,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 135,
          "question": "What happens to the body of the boy who is killed during the ritual in Chapter 9: “A View to a Death”?",
          "options": [
            "It is impaled on a stick.",
            "It is carried away by the tide.",
            "It is eaten by vultures.",
            "It is eaten by boars."
          ],
          "answer": "It is carried away by the tide."
        },
        {
          "number": 136,
          "question": "Where does the narrator say a great scab had formed on Ralph in the opening of Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "On his neck.",
            "On his arm.",
            "On his knee.",
            "On his chest."
          ],
          "answer": "On his knee."
        },
        {
          "number": 137,
          "question": "What does Piggy say Sam and Eric are doing when Ralph arrives at the camp in the beginning of Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "Gathering fruit.",
            "Hunting pigs.",
            "Gathering firewood.",
            "Going to Jack’s camp."
          ],
          "answer": "Gathering firewood."
        },
        {
          "number": 138,
          "question": "What word from Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses” means to make gestures in an excited manner?",
          "options": [
            "Gesticulate.",
            "Revere.",
            "Pontificate",
            "Luxuriate."
          ],
          "answer": "Gesticulate."
        },
        {
          "number": 139,
          "question": "In Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses,” Ralph claims that what happened during the ritual was murder. What does Piggy desperately claim it was instead?",
          "options": [
            "An accident.",
            "A sign of power.",
            "Self-protection.",
            "A religious act."
          ],
          "answer": "An accident."
        },
        {
          "number": 140,
          "question": "Ralph tells Piggy in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses,” “I’m frightened. Of” what?",
          "options": [
            "“The beast.”",
            "“Simon.”",
            "“Jack.”",
            "“Us.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Simon.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 141,
          "question": "Who stops Roger as he approaches the Castle Rock, saying “Halt! Who goes there?” in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Roger.",
            "Stanley.",
            "Wilfred."
          ],
          "answer": "Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 142,
          "question": "It is revealed to Roger in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses” that Jack got angry at what boy and had him tied up so that he can be beaten?",
          "options": [
            "Wilfred.",
            "Stanley.",
            "Roger.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Wilfred."
        },
        {
          "number": 143,
          "question": "What colors of face paint is Jack described as wearing in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "Black and blue.",
            "Red and white.",
            "Red and green.",
            "Brown and black."
          ],
          "answer": "Red and white."
        },
        {
          "number": 144,
          "question": "Which boy interrupts Jack when he is talking about the beast appearing in disguise to say, “But didn’t we, didn’t we--?” in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "Wilfred.",
            "Roger.",
            "Stanley.",
            "Maurice."
          ],
          "answer": "Stanley."
        },
        {
          "number": 145,
          "question": "What word is used in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses” to mean pertaining to the study of religious truth or divinity?",
          "options": [
            "Political.",
            "Vicissitude.",
            "Peripheral.",
            "Theological."
          ],
          "answer": "Theological."
        },
        {
          "number": 146,
          "question": "Who asks Jack in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses,” “What’ll we use for lighting the fire”?",
          "options": [
            "Maurice.",
            "Johnny.",
            "Simon.",
            "Bill."
          ],
          "answer": "Bill."
        },
        {
          "number": 147,
          "question": "Which of the boys volunteer to go along with Jack to steal fire from the other camp that night in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "Bill and Stewart.",
            "James and Peter.",
            "Maurice and Roger.",
            "Robert and Simon."
          ],
          "answer": "Maurice and Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 148,
          "question": "Piggy says as they relight the fire in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses,” “If only we could make a” what?",
          "options": [
            "\"Fan.\"",
            "\"Saw.\"",
            "\"Raft.\"",
            "\"Radio.\""
          ],
          "answer": "\"Radio.\""
        },
        {
          "number": 149,
          "question": "By what name does Ralph refer to Jack’s followers in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses”?",
          "options": [
            "“The Pig-killers.”",
            "“The Painteds.”",
            "“The Blues.”",
            "“The Reds.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“The Reds.”"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 11,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 150,
          "question": "As Ralph drifts to sleep in Chapter 10: “The Shell and the Glasses,” he imagines to himself, “Supposing they could be transported home by jet, then before morning they would land at that big airfield” where?",
          "options": [
            "“In New York.”",
            "“In Wiltshire.”",
            "“In London.”",
            "“In Manchester.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“In Wiltshire.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 151,
          "question": "What does the word “myopia” mean, as used in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "Nearsightedness.",
            "Betrayal.",
            "Farsightedness.",
            "Unworthiness."
          ],
          "answer": "Nearsightedness."
        },
        {
          "number": 152,
          "question": "Who says at the suggestion of going to Castle Rock to talk to Jack about Piggy’s glasses, “We ought to take spears,” in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Percival.",
            "Piggy.",
            "Sam."
          ],
          "answer": "Sam."
        },
        {
          "number": 153,
          "question": "Who does Piggy say was murdered in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "Roger.",
            "Robert.",
            "Simon.",
            "Jack."
          ],
          "answer": "Simon."
        },
        {
          "number": 154,
          "question": "Who suggests that the boys use their socks like caps in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "Eric.",
            "Ralph.",
            "Percival.",
            "Piggy."
          ],
          "answer": "Eric."
        },
        {
          "number": 155,
          "question": "Ralph says to the boys in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock” that when they approach Jack’s camp “we won’t be painted because we aren’t” what?",
          "options": [
            "“Idiots.”",
            "“Savages.”",
            "“Jack’s followers.”",
            "“Hunters.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Savages.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 156,
          "question": "What does the word “propitiate” mean, as used in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "To appease.",
            "To gather.",
            "To worship.",
            "To propel."
          ],
          "answer": "To appease."
        },
        {
          "number": 157,
          "question": "As Ralph’s remaining tribe heads toward Jack’s fortress in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock,” the narrator says, “Behind [Ralph] came the twins, worried now for a while but full of” what?",
          "options": [
            "“Vitriol and violence.”",
            "“Love for their leader.”",
            "“Unquenchable vitality.”",
            "“Obvious curiosity.”"
          ],
          "answer": "“Unquenchable vitality.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 158,
          "question": "In Chapter 11: “Castle Rock,” the narrator says, “There was no sign left of the storm, and the beach was swept clean like a blade that has been scoured.” What literary technique is used in this sentence?",
          "options": [
            "Religious allusion.",
            "Simile.",
            "Assonance.",
            "Onomatopoeia."
          ],
          "answer": "Simile."
        },
        {
          "number": 159,
          "question": "Who calls to Ralph and the others as they approach Jack’s fortress in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock,” saying “Halt! Who goes there?”",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Simon.",
            "Phil.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 160,
          "question": "Who responds when Ralph asks where Jack is in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock,” saying “He’s hunting. And he said we weren’t to let you in”?",
          "options": [
            "Phil.",
            "Bill.",
            "Robert.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 161,
          "question": "What lies on the ground behind Jack and his hunters when they emerge from the forest toward Ralph, Piggy, and the twins, in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock,”?",
          "options": [
            "A dead bird.",
            "A dead littlun.",
            "A headless pig.",
            "A pig’s head."
          ],
          "answer": "A headless pig."
        },
        {
          "number": 162,
          "question": "Who does Jack order his tribe to capture and tie up in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "Sam and Eric.",
            "Henry and Roger.",
            "Piggy and Ralph.",
            "Percival and Bill."
          ],
          "answer": "Sam and Eric."
        },
        {
          "number": 163,
          "question": "Piggy asks the crowd of boys during the showdown in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock,” “Which is better—to have rules and agree, or” what?",
          "options": [
            "“To call home for help?”",
            "“To not question authority?”",
            "“To hunt and kill?”",
            "“To find rescue?”"
          ],
          "answer": "“To hunt and kill?”"
        },
        {
          "number": 164,
          "question": "How many feet down does Piggy fall when he is hit by the rock in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "30 feet.",
            "20 feet.",
            "50 feet.",
            "40 feet."
          ],
          "answer": "40 feet."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "chapter_number": 12,
      "chapter_title": "",
      "multiple_choice": [
        {
          "number": 165,
          "question": "Who pulls the lever that drops the boulder, killing Piggy, in Chapter 11: “Castle Rock”?",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Bill.",
            "Jack.",
            "Roger."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 166,
          "question": "What is Ralph said to be laying in at the beginning of Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "A covert.",
            "A pig den.",
            "A cave.",
            "A pile of hay."
          ],
          "answer": "A covert."
        },
        {
          "number": 167,
          "question": "When Ralph looks back to Castle Rock from the forest in the beginning of Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters,” who does he see “sitting on guard at the top of the cliff” with “a spear in his left hand and tossing up a pebble and catching it again with the right”?",
          "options": [
            "Maurice.",
            "Roger.",
            "Simon.",
            "Robert."
          ],
          "answer": "Robert."
        },
        {
          "number": 168,
          "question": "What symbolic object in the novel was destroyed when Piggy died?",
          "options": [
            "The knife.",
            "The pig's head.",
            "The staff.",
            "The shell."
          ],
          "answer": "The shell."
        },
        {
          "number": 169,
          "question": "What word used in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters” means a kiss of peace?",
          "options": [
            "Mirage.",
            "Declivity.",
            "Pax.",
            "Vicissitude."
          ],
          "answer": "Pax."
        },
        {
          "number": 170,
          "question": "What does Ralph find in the forest to use as a weapon in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "A parachute.",
            "A stick that is pointed on two ends.",
            "A metal bear-trap.",
            "A dagger."
          ],
          "answer": "A stick that is pointed on two ends."
        },
        {
          "number": 171,
          "question": "Sam and Eric tell Ralph in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters” that Jack and who plant to hunt him tomorrow?",
          "options": [
            "Robert.",
            "Maurice.",
            "Roger.",
            "Johnny."
          ],
          "answer": "Roger."
        },
        {
          "number": 172,
          "question": "What is the first tactic that Jack’s tribe uses to flush Ralph from the thicket in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "They hurl boulders into it.",
            "They shoot a gun into the thicket.",
            "They flood it with water.",
            "They light the thicket on fire."
          ],
          "answer": "They hurl boulders into it."
        },
        {
          "number": 173,
          "question": "What is the second tactic used by Jack’s tribe to flush Ralph from the thicket in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "They shoot guns into the thicket.",
            "They send a wild boar into the thicket.",
            "They light the thicket on fire.",
            "They hurl boulders into the thicket."
          ],
          "answer": "They light the thicket on fire."
        },
        {
          "number": 174,
          "question": "What is the name of the littlun that first approaches the naval officer in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "Bill.",
            "Henry.",
            "Phil.",
            "Percival."
          ],
          "answer": "Percival."
        },
        {
          "number": 175,
          "question": "What is Jack described as wearing at his waist in the end of Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "A choir cloak.",
            "A cavalry pistol.",
            "A pair of broken spectacles.",
            "A mutilated pig’s head."
          ],
          "answer": "A pair of broken spectacles."
        },
        {
          "number": 176,
          "question": "The Coral Island: A Tale of the Pacific Ocean was written by what Scottish author?",
          "options": [
            "R. M. Ballantyne.",
            "Henry James.",
            "Mark Twain.",
            "Samuel Beckett."
          ],
          "answer": "R. M. Ballantyne."
        },
        {
          "number": 177,
          "question": "In the end of Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters,” Ralph is said to weep for “the end of innocence, the darkness of man’s heart,” and for the death of what “true, wise friend”?",
          "options": [
            "Simon.",
            "Sam.",
            "Jack.",
            "Piggy."
          ],
          "answer": "Piggy."
        },
        {
          "number": 178,
          "question": "In the ending of Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters,” the narrator notes that when the children all begin weeping, “The officer, surrounded by these noises, was moved and a little” what?",
          "options": [
            "\"Angry.\"",
            "“Embarrassed.”",
            "“Overwhelmed.”",
            "\"Emotional.\""
          ],
          "answer": "“Embarrassed.”"
        },
        {
          "number": 179,
          "question": "What does the officer say drew his crew to the island in Chapter 12: “Cry of the Hunters”?",
          "options": [
            "The sounds of screaming.",
            "The smoke from the fire.",
            "The sight of the airplane wreckage.",
            "The sound of gunfire."
          ],
          "answer": "The smoke from the fire."
        },
        {
          "number": 180,
          "question": "Which of the following is one of the central themes in Lord of the Flies?",
          "options": [
            "Political corruption.",
            "Beauty versus ugliness.",
            "Civility versus savagery.",
            "The betrayal of the mother."
          ],
          "answer": "Civility versus savagery."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}